

Collins Kiprop Kiptanui

Nationality: Kenyan Date of birth: 10/05/1996 Phone number: (+254) 706767859

Phone number: (+49) 17660801083 Email address: collinskiprop6@gmail.com

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/collins-kiprop-419b55190

Website: <u>collinskiptanui.github.io</u>

O Home: Vogelsang 121, 38118 Braunschweig (Germany)

ABOUT ME

I am a Data Scientist with a strong mathematical background and experience in using predictive modelling, data processing, machine learning, cloud computing, SQL and data mining algorithms to solve challenging business problems. I am involved in python open source community and passionate about utilizing the resources in data science to solve problems in different fields.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Data Analyst

Trans Tech International Company Limited [01/08/2021 - 31/12/2021]

City: Nairobi **Country:** Kenya

- 1. Identify and define the objectives of an assigned marketing research project; determines the best methods to use to meet those objectives.
- 2. Draft questionnaires, polls, surveys, and other data collection resources.
- 3. Research and compile data related to current product market, customer demographics and interest, and factors influencing product demand; analyze results to identify ways of maximizing sales and market penetration of current products.
- 4. Compile data related to competitors products such as pricing, sales, and marketing or distribution methodology.
- 5. Summarize and analyze data; make recommendations related to research findings.

Technical Mentor

Moringa School [06/01/2020 - 31/07/2020]

City: Nairobi Country: Kenya

- 1. Work effectively with relevant administrative, technical and academic staff in the School and across the Institution.
- 2. Actively support student recruitment including participation in class.
- 3. Teach students relevant data science skills and fundamental.

Statistics and Data analysis intern

Kenya Medical Research Institute [01/10/2018 – 31/12/2019]

City: Nairobi **Country:** Kenya

Studies:

- 1. Assessing health factors and Experiences associated with Khat handling, and chewing in selected areas in Kenya.
- 2. A Baseline Survey for Nestle Health kids program roll out in schools in Meru, Murang'a, and Nyeri counties.
- 3. NHIF Survey; A study to determine whether the KEMRI employees are studied with their NHIF cover. Responsibilities:
 - 1. Executing data quality protocols and internal quality checks to ensure complete and accurate databases are maintained.
 - 2. Data collection, data cleaning, data analysis and presentation to a panel of scientists.
 - 3. Designing XLS format for the data collection tools for Open Data Kit (ODK) to enhance electronic data collection.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master's Degree in Data Science

Technical University of Braunschweig [28/04/2022 – Current]

Address: Universitätspl. 2, 38106 Braunschweig, 38106 Braunschweig (Germany)

Website: https://www.tu-braunschweig.de/

Bachelor of Science in Actuarial Science

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology [10/09/2014 - 28/11/2019]

Address: P.O. Box 62000 - 00200 NAIROBI, KENYA, P.O. Box 62000 - 00200 Nairobi (Kenya)

Website: http://www.jkuat.ac.ke/

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education

Kapsabet Boys High School [13/03/2010 - 04/11/2014]

Address: P.O Box 10, C 36, Kapsabet, P.O Box 10, C 36, Kapsabet, Kenya Kapsabet (Kenya)

Website: http://kapsabet.boys.high.school.co.ke/

Kenya Certificate of Primary Education

Roseve Educational Center [08/01/2005 – 15/10/2009] **Address:** P.O. Box 657, Kapsabet, P.O. Box 657, Kapsabet

Website: http://roseve.ac.ke/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Swahili | English | Kalenjin

Other language(s):

German

LISTENING A2 READING A2 WRITING A2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION A2 SPOKEN INTERACTION A2

DIGITAL SKILLS

Data Gathering, Data Processing, Data Visualization, Data Analysis / SQL (MySQL) / Cloud computing / Software Architecture / Machine learning / Git / HTML / CSS / Python / R program / JavaScript

RECOMMENDATIONS

Colleague

Name: Anthony Mwangi

Phone number: (+254) 716344564 Email: <u>fiabletraders@gmail.com</u>

Director at Trans-tech international Company Limited

Colleague

Name: Maxmiller Keitany

Phone number: (+254) 724701697 Email: kmaxmiller@gmail.com

Prosecutor at Office of Director of Public Prosecution

Statistician- Kenya Medical Research Institute

Name: Nelson Ouma

Phone number: (+254) 704722919 Email: nellomondis@gmail.com

My supervisor at the Kenya Medical Research Institute.